Earl Browder Papers
Earl Browder Papers
- Correspondence-subject files
  - Gebert, Boleslaw Konstantin, 1934 (Box 19)
  - General Motors Corporation, 1937; 1948 (Box 19)
  - Gerard, Mary, 1946 (Box 19)
  - Germans in the United States, undated (Box 19)
  - Gerson, S. W., undated (Box 19)
  - Gerstovich, G. B., 1948 (Box 19)
  - Gilberton Company, 1946 (Box 19)
  - [J.K.] Gill Co., 1948 (Box 19)
  - Gilmore, Eddy, 1946 (Box 19)
  - Giraud, Henri Honoré, 1943 (Box 19)
  - Gladkov, M., 1947 (Box 20)
  - Glamour, 1947 (Box 20)
  - Global Press, Inc., 1947 (Box 20)
  - Gold, Mike, 1941 (Box 20)
  - Goldman, Marcus I., 1943 (Box 20)
  - Goldway, Dave, 1945 (Box 20)
  - Good Housekeeping, 1947 (Box 20)
  - Gordon, Eugene, 1944 (Box 20)
  - Gorman, Patrick E., 1944 (Box 20)
  - Green, Elizabeth, 1940 (Box 20)
  - Gridiron Club (Box 20)
  - Grigoriev, Nikifor, 1943 (Box 20)
  - Grolier Information Service, 1947 (Box 20)
  - Grossman, Cornell, 1945 (Box 20)
  - Grumman Aircraft Engineering Corp., 1943 (Box 20)
  - Guardian, Cape Town, South Africa, 1945 (Box 20)
  - H, 1942-1960 (Box 20)
  - Haithcox, John P., 1967 (Box 20)
  - Haldeman-Julius Publications, Girard, Kansas, 1947 (Box 20)
  - Hall, Gus, undated (Box 20)
  - Hall, Robert F., 1940 (Box 20)
  - Halula, Winifred, 1963 (Box 20)
  - Hamilton College, 1948 (Box 20)
  - Hammett, Molly, 1961-1969 (Box 20)
  - Handler, Morton, 1956-1965 (Box 20)
  - Hanson, Earl Parker, 1946 (Box 20)
  - Harcourt, Brace and Company, 1946; 1947 (Box 20)
  - Harper & Brothers, 1946-1960; 1963 (Box 20)
  - Harper's Bazaar, See Harper & Brothers.
  - Harper's Magazine, See Harper & Brothers.
  - Harris, Thomas L., 1943 (Box 20)
  - Hart Publishing Co., 1948 (Box 20)
  - Hartman, George W., 1936 (Box 20)
  - Harvard Business Review, 1947 (Box 20)
  - Harvard Cooperative Society, Inc., 1948 (Box 20)
  - Harvard Get-Together Club, 1936 (Box 20)
  - Harvard Law Review, 1947 (Box 20)
  - Harvard Student Union, 1940 (Box 20)
  - Harvard University, 1947; 1948,; 1961 (Box 20)
  - Harvey Associates, 1958; 1960 (Box 20)
  - Hathaway, Clarence A., 1930; 1938,; 1940 (Box 20)
  - Headlines and What's Behind Them, 1953 (Box 20)
  - [W.S.] Heinman & Company, 1947 (Box 20)
  - Heller, Abe A., 1941-1952 (Box 21)
  - Hemingway, Ernest, See Speiser, Maurice J. and Herbert A.
  - [Norman W.] Henley Publishing Company, 1947 (Box 21)
  - Herald Tribune Books, 1946 (Box 21)
  - Hervé, Pierre, See La Nouvelle Réforme.
  - Hinman, Ithamar B., 1938 (Box 21)
  - Hofstra College, Hempstead, Long Island, NY, 1962; 1963 (Box 21)
  - [Henry] Holt and Company, Inc., Publishers, 1946 (Box 21)
  - Honduras, undated (Box 21)
  - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1939; 1947 (Box 21)
  - Houphouët-Boigny, Félix, 1946 (Box 21)
  - Housing Progress Magazine, 1947 (Box 21)
  - Howard, Milton, undated (Box 21)
  - Hsieh, Tehyi, undated (Box 21)
  - Hudicourt, Max L., undated (Box 21)
  - Hungary, 1945 (Box 21)
  - Hunt, R. N. Carew, 1958; 1959 (Box 21)
  - Huntington, Hester, 1942 (Box 21)
    See also International Labor Defense.
  - [H.R.] Huntting Company, 1948 (Box 21)
  - Hutchins, Grace, 1941 (Box 21)
  - Hutchinson & Co. (Publishers) Ltd., London, 1947 (Box 21)
  - Ibárruri Gómez, Dolores, See Communist Party, Spain.
  - Imperial War Museum, London, 1945 (Box 21)
  - "In Defense of the Bill of Rights", 1939 (Box 21)
  - Independent Workers Alliance of Minnesota, 1938 (Box 21)
  - India Council for Freedom and Democracy, 1942 (Box 21)
  - India News, 1942; undated (Box 21)
  - Indiana Unemployed Union, 1935 (Box 21)
  - Industrial Association of San Francisco, 1936 (Box 21)
  - Industrial Bulletin, 1948 (Box 21)
  - Industrial Equipment News, 1946; 1947 (Box 21)
  - Industrial Press, Inc., 1947 (Box 21)
  - Industrial Workers of the World (IWW), 1923 (Box 21)
  - Ingersoll & Brennan, New York, NY, 1946; 1947 (Box 21)
  - Institute for Research in Biography, 1947 (Box 21)
  - Institute of Pacific Relations, 1942; 1951 (Box 21)
  - Institute of Public Affairs, Charlottesville, Virginia, 1939 (Box 21)
  - Institute of the Aeronautical Sciences, 1948 (Box 21)
  - Inter-Continent News, 1940; 1943 (Box 21)
  - International Brigade Association, 1942 (Box 21)
  - International Committee for Political Prisoners, 1935-1947 (Box 21)
  - International Committee of Coordination and Information for Aid to Republican Spain, 1938 (Box 21)
  - International Culture and Service Society, Shanghai, China, 1948 (Box 21)
  - International Federation of Business and Professional Women, 1944 (Box 21)
  - International Labor Defense, 1929-1944 (Box 22)
  - International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union, 1943 (Box 22)
  - International News Service, 1956 (Box 22)
  - International Press Correspondence, 1927 (Box 22)
  - International Publishers Co., Inc., 1947; 1948 (Box 22)
  - International Trade Union Committee of Negro Workers of the R.I.L.U., 1930 (Box 22)
  - International Union of Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers, 1941 (Box 22)
  - International Union of United Automobile, Aircraft and Agricultural Implement Workers, 1942 (Box 22)
  - International Workers Order, 1940; 1942,; 1944 (Box 22)
  - Interscience Publishers, Inc, 1946; 1947 (Box 22)
  - The Iron Age, 1946 (Box 22)
  - The Island Press Cooperative, Inc., 1946 (Box 22)
  - Italians in America, undated (Box 22)
  - Italy Today, 1945 (Box 22)
  - Izdatburo, Moscow, USSR, 1945-1949 (Box 22)
  - J, 1938-1946; 1964 (Box 22)
  - Jackson, Harry, See California vs. Harry Jackson.
  - Jackson, John, 1920 (Box 22)
  - Jaffe, Philip, 1947; 1954,; 1959,; 1962 (Box 22)
  - Januszewski, Frank, 1945 (Box 22)
  - Jay, Norman, 1943 (Box 22)
  - Jeffers, Minnie, 1945-1962 (Box 22)
  - The Jefferson School of Social Science, New York, NY, 1945 (Box 22)
  - Jencks, Clinton E., 1955 (Box 22)
  - Jewish Committee for a United American Labor Party, 1943 (Box 22)
  - Jewish Labor Committee, See Grigoriev, Nikifor.
  - Jewish Life, 1957 (Box 22)
  - Jewish Peoples Committee for United Action Against Fascism and Anti-Semitism, 1943 (Box 22)
  - Jiménez-Malaret, René, 1944 (Box 22)
  - The John Reed Society of Harvard University, 1937 (Box 22)
  - Johns Hopkins Press, 1946 (Box 22)
  - Johnson, Beatrice, 1943 (Box 22)
  - Johnson, F. Ernest, 1959; 1962,; 1963 (Box 22)
  - Johnson, William N., 1947 (Box 22)
  - [Walter J.] Johnson Rare and Modern Books New York, NY, 1947 (Box 22)
  - Johnstone, Jack, 1929; 1934,; 1940,; 1942 (Box 23)
  - Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee, 1939; 1942 (Box 23)
  - Jordan, Virgil, 1940; 1944 (Box 23)
  - Jugoslav Workers Bookshop, Chicago, Illinois, 1930 (Box 23)
  - K, 1942-1964 (Box 23)
  - Kahn, Albert E., undated (Box 23)
  - Kamp, Joseph P., See Headlines and What's Behind Them.
  - Kansas City Star, 1948 (Box 23)
  - Keating, Kenneth Barnard, 1959 (Box 23)
  - Kennan, George Frost, 1957 (Box 23)
  - Kennedy, Robert Francis, 1954 (Box 23)
  - Kent, Rockwell, 1939; 1942 (Box 23)
  - The Kenyon Review, 1947 (Box 23)
  - King, Carol, 1941-1948 (Box 23)
  - King, Eleanor, 1946; 1947 (Box 23)
  - King, Paul H., 1943 (Box 23)
  - Kiplinger Washington Letter, 1944 (Box 23)
  - Kiwanis Club of Yonkers, NY, 1939 (Box 23)
  - [Alfred A.] Knopf, Inc., 1946-1948 (Box 23)
  - Knudsen, Hugo, 1943 (Box 23)
  - Kohlberg, Alfred, 1945; 1946,; 1954 (Box 23)
  - Kotoku, Shusui, 1944 (Box 23)
  - Kovnat, Sam, 1943 (Box 23)
  - Ku Klux Klan, 1940; 1942 (Box 23)
    See also Black Legion.
  - L, 1936-1963 (Box 23)
  - Labor Analyst, 1946 (Box 23)
  - Labor Lyceum, Rochester, NY, 1947 (Box 23)
  - Lacerda, Fernando, 1944 (Box 23)
  - Lachatanere, Romulo, 1943 (Box 23)
  - LaFollette, Robert Marion, Jr., undated (Box 23)
  - Lamont, Corliss, 1942; 1943,; 1959 (Box 23)
  - Lampe, Alfred, 1944 (Box 23)
  - Landy, Avrom, undated (Box 23)
  - Lange, Oscar Ryszard, 1943 (Box 24)
  - Lannon, Albert Vetere, undated (Box 24)
  - Laptev, I., 1948 (Box 24)
  - Lash, Joseph P., 1963 (Box 24)
  - Laski, Harold Joseph, 1938 (Box 24)
  - Lasky, Victor, See Spadea syndicate.
  - Latin America, 1935; 1943,; 1944 (Box 24)
  - Law, Richard Kidston (Baron Coleraine), 1942 (Box 24)
  - Lawyers Guild Review, 1947 (Box 24)
  - Lazarsfeld, Paul, 1945 (Box 24)
  - League of American Writers, 1938 (Box 24)
  - League for Industrial Democracy, 1934 (Box 24)
  - Lebedev-Polyanski, Pavel Ivanovich, 1946 (Box 24)
  - Lefkowitz, Louis J., 1937 (Box 24)
  - Lehman, Herbert Henry, 1942; 1958 (Box 24)
  - Lehman Corporation, 1948 (Box 24)
  - Levallois, Maurice, 1945 (Box 24)
  - Levine, Isaac Don, 1935; 1945,; 1947 (Box 24)
  - Lesueur, Meridel, 1941 (Box 24)
  - Libby, Frederick J., See National Council for Prevention of War.
  - Liberal Party of New York State, 1946 (Box 24)
  - Liberty, 1939; 1944,; 1947 (Box 24)
  - Lieber, Maxim, 1944 (Box 24)
  - Life, 1943; 1945,; 1947,; 1948 (Box 24)
  - Linde Air Products Company, 1946 (Box 24)
  - Lindley, Ernest K., 1938 (Box 24)
  - [J.B.] Lippincott Company, 1947; 1948 (Box 24)
  - Lipset, Seymour Martin, 1960 (Box 24)
  - Literary agents, undated (Box 24)
  - Little, Herbert, 1950 (Box 24)
  - Little, Brown & Company, 1946-1949 (Box 24)
  - Lloyd, David, 1947 (Box 24)
  - Lloyd, William Bross, Jr., 1939 (Box 24)
  - Lombardo Toledano, Vincente, 1945 (Box 24)
  - Look, 1947 (Box 24)
  - Los Angeles County Law Library, 1948 (Box 24)
  - Los Angeles Forum, 1942 (Box 24)
  - Los Angeles Public Library, 1948 (Box 24)
  - Los Angeles School of Social Science, 1950; 1961 (Box 24)
  - Lovestone, Jay, See Communist Party USA, opposition.
  - Luce, Clare Boothe, 1946 (Box 24)
  - Lumber Workers' Industrial Union of Canada, 1924 (Box 24)
  - Lumpkin, Katharine, 1946 (Box 24)
  - Lyons, Eugene, 1945 (Box 24)
  - M, 1940-1963 (Box 24)
  - MacDermot, Nial, 1959 (Box 24)
  - Mackay Radio, 1947 (Box 24)
  - The MacMillan Company, 1946-1948 (Box 24)
  - Mademoiselle, 1947 (Box 24)
  - Magazine House Publishers, 1946 (Box 24)
  - Magazine of Art, 1947 (Box 24)
  - Magil, Abe, 1945 (Box 25)
  - Mann, Tom, 1937 (Box 25)
  - Manning Association, North Billerica, Massachusetts, 1922 (Box 25)
  - Mao Zedong, 1945; 1948 (Box 25)
  - Marcantonio, Vito, 1943 (Box 25)
  - Marinello, Juan, 1941 (Box 25)
  - Maritime Workers Union, 1938 (Box 25)
  - Markoff, Abraham, 1937 (Box 25)
  - Marty, André, 1944 (Box 25)
  - "Marx-Lenin-Engels-Browder on America", See Mindel, Jacob.
  - Maverick, Maury, 1940 (Box 25)
  - May-Bailey Bill (HR 1752), 1945 (Box 25)
  - McCall's Magazine, 1947 (Box 25)
  - McClure, Wallace, 1947 (Box 25)
  - [A.C.] McClurg & Company, 1948 (Box 25)
  - McCormick, Anne O'Hare, 1945 (Box 25)
  - McGraw Hill Book Company, Inc., 1944; 1946-1948,; 1963 (Box 25)
  - [David] McKay Company, 1949 (Box 25)
  - McKenney, Ruth, See Bransten, Richard.
  - McNaboe, John, See New York Senate Judiciary Committee.
  - McWilliams, Carey, See California Department of Industrial Relations.
  - Meadows, Ann, 1959 (Box 25)
  - "Meet the Press," Mutual Broadcasting System, 1946; 1949,; 1950 (Box 25)
  - Mellon Institute of Industrial Research, 1947 (Box 25)
  - Memorial Day Massacre of 1937 (Box 25)
  - Menzel, Donald H., 1947 (Box 25)
  - Meredith Press, See Duell, Sloan & Pearce, Inc.
  - Merrill, Lewis, See United Office and Professional Workers of America.
  - Merriman, Robert Hale, 1943 (Box 25)
  - Merv Griffin Show, See Anthony Productions, Inc.
  - [Julian] Messner Publishers, Inc, 1947 (Box 25)
  - Metal Workers Industrial League, 1929 (Box 25)
  - Mexico, 1940 (Box 25)
  - Michigan CIO Council, 1943 (Box 25)
  - Michigan State Library, 1948 (Box 25)
  - Midol, Lucien, 1944 (Box 25)
  - The Militant, See Socialist Workers Party.
  - Miller, Marion, 1940 (Box 25)
  - Mills, Sheldon, 1944 (Box 25)
  - Mindel, Jacob, 1942; undated; 4 folders of 6 (Box 25)
  - Mindel, Jacob, 1942; undated; 2 folders of 6 (Box 26)
  - Minor, Robert, 1930-1945; 2 folders (Box 26)
  - Minot, Francis, 1945 (Box 26)
  - Minton, Bruce (pseudonym), See Bransten, Richard.
  - Mitchell, Broadus, 1958; 1959,; 1961 (Box 26)
  - Modern Music, 1946 (Box 26)
  - Monthly Review, 1950; 1956 (Box 26)
  - Moore Stationery Company, Topeka, Kansas, 1948 (Box 26)
  - Morgan, Thomas H., 1946; 1950 (Box 26)
  - Morris, Robert John, 1954-1957 (Box 26)
  - [William] Morris Agency, 1955 (Box 26)
  - Morrow, Felix, See University Books, Inc.
  - [William] Morrow & Co., Inc., 1935 (Box 26)
  - Morse, Eugene, 1942 (Box 26)
  - Mostel, Zero, undated (Box 26)
  - Mowrer, Edgar Ansel, 1946-1948 (Box 26)
  - Murphy, Jack T., 1960-1963 (Box 26)
  - Murphy, Ray, 1957 (Box 26)
  - Murphy, William Francis, 1938 (Box 26)
  - Musette Publishers, Inc., 1947 (Box 26)
  - Musical America, 1946 (Box 26)
  - Musical Courier, 1946; 1947 (Box 26)
  - Musical Digest, 1947; 1948 (Box 26)
  - Musical Quarterly, 1947 (Box 26)
  - N, 1930; 1946,; undated (Box 27)
  - Nance, E.C., 1938 (Box 27)
  - The Nation, 1946; 1947,; 1951 (Box 27)
  - Nation's Business, 1947 (Box 27)
  - National Association of Authors and Journalists, 1967 (Box 27)
  - National Association of Manufacturers, 1942 (Box 27)
  - National Association of Secondary-School Principals, 1939 (Box 27)
  - National Citizens Political Action Committee, 1944 (Box 27)
  - National Conference of Entertainment Industry for War Activities, 1943 (Box 27)
  - National Conference of Social Work, Cleveland, OH, 1944 (Box 27)
  - National Conference of Union Labor legionnaires, 1943 (Box 27)
  - National Council for Prevention of War, 1937; 1938 (Box 27)
  - National Council of the Arts, Sciences, and Professions, 1951 (Box 27)
  - National Council of Soviet American Friendship, 1947 (Box 27)
  - National Emergency Civil Liberties Committee, 1969 (Box 27)
  - National Federation for Constitutional Liberties, 1942; 1943 (Box 27)
  - National Front of Liberation (Free French) Morocco, 1943 (Box 27)
  - National Geographic, 1947 (Box 27)
  - National Jewish Hospital at Denver, 1945 (Box 27)
  - National Lawyers' Guild, 1940 (Box 27)
  - National Maritime Union, 1942; 1944 (Box 27)
  - National Religion and Labor Foundation, 1936 (Box 27)
  - National Service legislation, 1942 (Box 27)
  - National Sharecroppers Fund, Inc, 1962 (Box 27)
  - National Socialist Press Service, 1932 (Box 27)
  - National Synarchist Union Mexico, See Sinarchismo.
  - National Unemployment Council, See Workers Alliance of America.
  - National Union for Social Justice, 1941; See The Christian Front (Box 27)
  - National Wartime Conference of the Professions, the Sciences, the Arts and White Collar Fields, 1943 (Box 27)
  - National Women's Trade Union League of America, 1943; 1945 (Box 27)
  - Natural History Magazine, 1947 (Box 27)
  - Nearing, Scott, 1929; 1936 (Box 27)
  - Nebraska State Journal, 1948 (Box 27)
  - Negro Freedom Rally, Madison Square Garden, NY, 1945 (Box 27)
  - "Negroes in the Army", undated (Box 27)
  - Nelson, N. J., 1946 (Box 27)
  - [Thomas] Nelson and Sons, 1958 (Box 27)
  - New Century Publishers, 1947 (Box 27)
  - New Committee for Publications, 1946; 1947; 3 folders (Box 28)
  - New England Conference on Civil Liberties, 1940 (Box 28)
  - New Leader, 1935; 1942 (Box 28)
  - New Masses, 1942; 1947 (Box 28)
  - New Republic, 1938; 1943,; 1946-1949 (Box 28)
  - New School for Social Research, 1958 (Box 28)
  - New York Chamber of Commerce, 1935 (Box 28)
  - New York City, New York Assembly Districts, 1930 (Box 28)
  - New York City Board of Elections, 1940 (Box 28)
  - New York Herald Tribune, 1936; 1946-1948 (Box 28)
  - New York Journal and American, undated (Box 28)
  - New York Post, 1948 (Box 28)
  - New York Public Library, 1939 (Box 28)
  - New York Senate Judiciary Committee, 1938 (Box 28)
  - New York State Constitution proposal for Constitutional Convention, undated (Box 28)
  - New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations, Ithaca, NY, 1957 (Box 28)
  - New York Society of Security Analysts, 1946 (Box 28)
  - New York Telephone Co., 1946; 1948 (Box 28)
  - New York Times, 1943; 1946-1948,; 1952,; 1956,; 1957,; 1963 (Box 28)
  - New York University, 1935; 1948,; 1951,; 1956 (Box 28)
  - The New Yorker, 1947 (Box 28)
  - New Zealand Government Trade Commissioner, 1948 (Box 28)
  - The News, New York, NY, 1964 (Box 28)
  - Newsday, Garden City, Long Island, NY, 1957 (Box 28)
  - Newspaper Guild of New York, 1945 (Box 28)
  - Newsweek, 1947 (Box 28)
  - Newton (Massachusetts) Community Forum, 1939 (Box 29)
  - Ney, Lew (pseudonym), 1942 (Box 29)
  - "Night Beat," Dumont Broadcasting Corporation, 1957 (Box 29)
  - Nikolauk, Domenica N., 1959 (Box 29)
  - Noble & Noble Publishers, Inc, 1946 (Box 29)
  - Normington-Rawling, James, 1962; 1964 (Box 29)
  - North, Joseph, 1939; 1942,; 1944 (Box 29)
  - North American Aviation, Inc, 1943 (Box 29)
  - North American Newspaper Alliance, Inc, 1946-1948; 1954,; 1960,; 1964 (Box 29)
  - [W.N.] Norton & Company, Inc., 1947; 1948 (Box 29)
  - La Nouvelle Réforme, 1957; 1958 (Box 29)
  - Novy Mir (Новый Мир), undated (Box 29)
  - O, 1943-1946 (Box 29)
  - Oak, Liston M., 1945 (Box 29)
  - [Harold] Ober Associates, 1951; 1952 (Box 29)
  - [F.M.] O'Brien Antiquarian Bookseller, 1942 (Box 29)
  - The Observer, London, 1963 (Box 29)
  - OGIZ, Moscow, USSR, 1946 (Box 29)
  - O'Holloran, H.R., 1945 (Box 29)
  - Oklahoma Criminal Court of Appeals, 1943 (Box 29)
  - Omnibook, 1946 (Box 29)
  - "Open Mind", See WNBC.
  - Opinion: A Journal of Jewish Life and Letters, 1939 (Box 29)
  - Originator, 1947 (Box 29)
  - Orthodox Old Catholic Church in America, 1936 (Box 29)
  - O'Sheel, Shaemas, 1942; 1944 (Box 29)
  - Oxford University Press, 1946-1948 (Box 29)
  - P, 1939-1947 (Box 29)
  - P.R. Club, Communist Party (expelled), 1947 (Box 29)
  - Packaging Parade, 1947 (Box 29)
  - Pageant, 1947 (Box 29)
  - Paine, Merlin M., 1960 (Box 29)
  - Pan American Labor Convention, 1942 (Box 29)
  - Pan American Labor Federation, 1943 (Box 29)
  - Pantheon Books, Inc, 1946-1948 (Box 29)
  - Panvor, 1937 (Box 29)
  - Parents' Magazine, 1947 (Box 29)
  - Park Theatre, New York, NY, 1879 (Box 29)
  - Parkway Community Council, Brooklyn, NY, 1947; 1949,; 1951 (Box 29)
  - Partido Socialista Popular de Cuba, See Communist Party, Cuba.
  - Pass, Joseph, 1934 (Box 29)
  - Pasadena City Schools, 1948 (Box 29)
  - Passaic Public Library, 1948 (Box 29)
  - Patterson, William L., 1942 (Box 29)
  - Peace Book Company, Hong Kong, 1967 (Box 29)
  - Pease, John William Beaumont (Lord Wardington), 1944 (Box 29)
  - Pegler, Westbrook, 1934-1942 (Box 30)
  - Pell, Mike (pseudonym), See Appelman, Mike.
  - Penguin Books, Inc., 1946; 1947 (Box 30)
  - Pennsylvania Congress for American Liberties, 1941 (Box 30)
  - Pennypacker, Anna M.W., 1943 (Box 30)
  - People of the State of New York vs. Morris U. Schappes, 1943 (Box 30)
  - People's Educational Association, 1944 (Box 30)
  - People's Institute of Applied Religion, Inc., 1944 (Box 30)
  - Pesenti, Antonio, undated (Box 30)
  - Phillips, Walton D., 1944 (Box 30)
  - Philosophical Library, Inc., 1947; 1948 (Box 30)
  - Pinpin Cooperative Press, Manila, Philippines, undated (Box 30)
  - Pitman Publishing Corporation, 1947 (Box 30)
  - Pittsburgh Central Labor Union, 1935 (Box 30)
  - P M Daily, 1942; 1946,; 1947 (Box 30)
  - Pocket Books, Inc., 1947 (Box 30)
  - Poland, 1937 (Box 30)
  - Poles in the USA, undated (Box 30)
  - Polish Telegraph Agency, London, England, 1945 (Box 30)
  - Polish Workers' Party, 1945 (Box 30)
  - Political Information Bulletin, 1938 (Box 30)
  - Political Science Quarterly, 1963 (Box 30)
  - Poll tax, 1943 (Box 30)
  - Pollitt, Harry, 1943 (Box 30)
  - Poltorak, A., 1952 (Box 30)
  - Popular Science, 1947 (Box 30)
  - Post-Hall Syndicate, Inc, 1952 (Box 30)
  - Post-War Forum, 1945 (Box 30)
  - Post-War Planning, 1942 (Box 30)
  - Powell, Adam Clayton, Jr., 1950 (Box 30)
  - Pravda, 1938-1942 (Box 30)
  - Prentice-Hall, Inc., 1947; 1948 (Box 30)
  - President's War Relief Control Board, 1944 (Box 30)
  - Preveden, Francis R., 1946 (Box 30)
  - Princeton University Library, 1947 (Box 30)
  - Princeton University Press, 1946-1949 (Box 30)
  - Princeton University Store, 1948 (Box 30)
  - The Progressive, 1947 (Box 30)
  - Progressive Architecture, 1947 (Box 30)
  - Progressive Citizens of America, 1946; 1947 (Box 30)
  - Progressive Party, 1948 (Box 30)
  - The Protestant, 1948 (Box 30)
  - Public Affairs Committee, Inc., 1949 (Box 30)
  - Publishers' Weekly, 1946 (Box 30)
  - Pueblos Hispanos, 1944 (Box 30)
    See also Corretjer, Juan Antonio.
  - Puerto Rico, 1943 (Box 30)
  - Q, 1937; 1943-1945,; 1956 (Box 30)
  - Quarterly Review of Literature, 1947 (Box 30)
  - Quigley Publications, 1947 (Box 30)
  - Quill, Michael J., 1950; 1956 (Box 30)
  - R, 1942-1946 (Box 31)
  - Rabello, Manoel, 1943 (Box 31)
  - Ragland, James, 1968 (Box 31)
  - Railroad Magazine, 1939 (Box 31)
  - Railway Labor Executives' Association, 1943 (Box 31)
  - Rajk, Laszlo, 1949 (Box 31)
  - Random House, Inc., 1938; 1946,; 1947 (Box 31)
  - Ransdell, Inc., Publishers, 1947 (Box 31)
  - Rautenstrauch, Walter, 1942 (Box 31)
  - Rawling, James Normington, See Normington-Rawling, James.
  - Rayden, Sid, 1943 (Box 31)
  - RCA Communications, Inc, 1946 (Box 31)
  - The Reader's Press, Inc., 1946 (Box 31)
  - Reader's Scope, 1945-1948 (Box 31)
  - Red International Committee of the United States and Canada, 1923 (Box 31)
  - Red International of Labor Unions, 1923-1930 (Box 31)
  - Red International of Labor Unions International Trade Union Committee of Negro Workers, 1931 (Box 31)
  - Reed, Ferdinanda W., 1942; 1945 (Box 31)
  - Reeve, Karl, 1930 (Box 31)
  - [Henry] Regnery Company, 1954 (Box 31)
  - Reichstag Fire Trial Anniversary, Carnegie Hall, 22 Dec 1943 (Box 31)
  - Reid, Helen Rogers, 1936 (Box 31)
  - Reinhold Publishing Corporation, 1946 (Box 31)
  - Reinstein, Boris, 1935 (Box 31)
  - Reitman, Alan, See American Civil Liberties Union.
  - Religion and Communism, undated (Box 31)
  - Remsen Press, undated (Box 31)
  - The Reporter, 1953 (Box 31)
  - Republic Steel Corporation, 1938 (Box 31)
  - Republican National Committee, 1940 (Box 31)
  - Research Bureau for Postwar Economics, See Russian Economic Institute.
  - Research Institute of America, 1946 (Box 31)
  - Revolutionary Worker's League, 1936 (Box 31)
  - Revyuk, Emil, 1942 (Box 31)
  - Reynall and Hitchcock, Inc., 1946; 1947 (Box 31)
  - Richard, Christian M.B., 1938 (Box 31)
    See also Declaration of Interdependence.
  - Richards, Augustus L., 1942; 1943 (Box 31)
  - Richards, Paul C., 1961-1964 (Box 31)
  - Riesel, Victor, 1956 (Box 31)
  - Ripps, Lillian, 1942 (Box 31)
  - Robb, Roger, 1951 (Box 31)
  - Robeson, Eslanda Goode, 1944 (Box 31)
  - Robeson, Paul, 1944 (Box 31)
  - Robinson, Earl, 1943 (Box 31)
  - Roca, Blas, See Communist Party, Cuba.
  - Rochester, Anna, 1943; 1945 (Box 31)
  - [H.G.] Roebuck and Son, Inc., 1955 (Box 31)
  - Rogge, O. John, 1939-1964 (Box 31)
  - Roman Catholic Church, 1938; 1939 (Box 32)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1939; 1944,; 1945 (Box 32)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano
    - Outgoing, 1942; 1943 (Box 32)
    - Incoming, 1936-1943 (Box 32)
  - The [Franklin D.] Roosevelt Series (NBC TV), 1962 (Box 32)
  - Roosevelt Victory Bandwagon, New York, 1944 (Box 32)
  - Ross, Lawrence, 1930 (Box 32)
  - Rossiter, Clinton, 1955; 1957 (Box 32)
  - Rougier, Louis, undated (Box 32)
  - Roumain, Jacques, 1944; 1945 (Box 32)
  - Roy Publishers, 1946 (Box 32)
  - Rucker, James Bernard, 1943 (Box 32)
  - Rudensky, Morris "Red", 1943 (Box 32)
  - Russell, Richard Brevard, Jr., 1957 (Box 32)
  - Russian Economic Institute, 1944 (Box 32)
  - Russian Social Democratic Party, 1924 (Box 32)
  - Russian War Relief, Inc., 1943 (Box 32)
  - Rutgers University, 1957 (Box 32)
  - Rutledge, Wiley Blount, Jr., 1944 (Box 32)
  - Ryack, Stephen, 1960 (Box 32)
  - Ryan, Frank, 1940 (Box 32)
  - Ryan, James G., 1972 (Box 32)
  - S, 1943-1960 (Box 32)
  - Sage, James, 1943 (Box 32)